FEBRUARY 22ND (MONDAY)
-Kazunari Toda. Haruko Nomura.
-Here.
-Kaori Hasebe.
-Koichi Hamada.
-Here.
-Satoru Fujinuma.
-Kazuma Horiguchi.
-Here.
Ma...
Kayo, you're late again.
-Yuko Matsumoto.
-Here.
-Misato Yanagihara.
-Osamu Yamoto.
-Here.
-Ami Yuki.
-Naoki Watanabe.
-Here.
All right, we're at the start of
another week. Let's all study hard.
Yes.
The reason Kayo is late on Mondays?
Yeah.
Do you know why, Satoru?
Because Saturdays are when
her mother hits her face.
She has to wait until the marks fade.
I see.
Did you not notice anything?
Well...
I guess I can tell you the truth.
But don't tell anyone.
I promise.
I've reported it to Child Services,
but Kayo's mother is never home,
so they haven't been able
to interview her.
What?
How could they be so useless?
But I'm sure she's abusing Kayo.
We just need her mother to admit it.
But once this happens...
Kayo won't be able to stay here.
I don't care as long as it means
Hinazuki is safe. Please hurry!
FEBRUARY 23RD (TUESDAY)
CLASS ATTENDANTS:
SATORU FUJINUMA, KAYO HINAZUKI
Good morning, Hinazuki.
Good morning.
CLASS ATTENDANTS:
SATORU FUJINUMA, KAYO HINAZUKI
Please be quiet.
-Okay.
-I'm collecting lunch money now.
Okay.
You need a compass and ruler
for art tomorrow,
so make sure you bring them.
Okay.
Did our assistants
collect lunch money?
Yes.
What's wrong, Satoru?
Mr. Yashiro.
I've lost everyone's lunch money.
What?
What? Why?
Mr. Yashiro.
I don't think it was lost.
I think it was stolen.
I suspect Hinazuki.
-Misato! What's your reason?
-Hinazuki's family is poor.
She doesn't pay for lunch.
I think we should look through
everyone's bags.
I agree!
She's right. Let's all look.
Come on! Let's look!
You're not looking, Kazu?
Why would I if I didn't take it?
See? I told you!
Shut up! I don't care if she's poor,
Hinazuki wouldn't steal!
Someone could be playing
a prank on her.
All right, everyone.
Kayo's a co-assistant, so it's
not strange she has the money.
Okay, back to our end-of-day meeting.
Fujinuma.
Thanks for that.
Don't mention it.
She was being really mean.
She's hated me for a long time.
But it wasn't always like that.
One time she invited me
to a Christmas party.
It was to show off
her big Christmas tree...
But still...
It was really beautiful.
FEBRUARY 24TH, 1988 (WEDNESDAY)
Hey.
I'd like to go out next Saturday.
Is it a date?
We're all going skiing.
Too bad. I would've
given you money for a date.
Seriously?!
So, it is a date.
You should bring her by here, too.
We can have some stew.
But Hinazuki is coming
for the birthday party.
Oh, Hinazuki from District Five?
Crap. I fell for her leading questions.
No surprise, coming from a
former Ishikari News employee.
Here. Be careful, okay?
Thanks.
Are you guys free this Saturday?
-Saturday?
-Yeah. You guys want to go skiing?
Oh, and Hinazuki will be coming, too.
What's going on, Fujinuma?
Sorry, Satoru.
I've already got plans for Saturday.
Besides, I bet you'd rather be
alone with Hinazuki.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Bye.
Bye. Bye.
What is it?
Oh, Hinazuki.
Saturday.
Come on a date with me.
But Saturdays...
My mom wants me home early
on Saturdays.
There's somewhere I want to take you.
I'll talk to her for you.
Okay.
I'd like to go somewhere with Hinazuki
this Saturday.
No.
Saturdays are when
Kayo helps around the house.
I can help, too. Then you'd
let her go afterwards, won't you?
I don't want your help.
Why don't you want
Hinazuki leaving the house?
I can think of several reasons.
Why would you want to hang out
with someone so cold?
I don't need a reason to save a friend.
Save?
Kayo.
What do you want to do?
Do you want to go out with him?
Get your head out of the clouds!
That's no way to speak to children.
Ms. Hinazuki.
Ms. Fujinuma.
This isn't your problem.
Half of it is my problem.
The children seem determined
to do something.
We should support them...as their parents.
Kayo, get inside.
Kayo!
-Should I have not done that?
-No, you were fine. Thank you.
I'm glad I followed you
when I saw you walking by.
You were following us?!
I'm obviously just kidding!
Anyway, Satoru.
-You'd better not quit halfway.
-Obviously!
Bye!
FEBRUARY 27TH (SATURDAY)
Hold on.
Here. Gloves.
It's cold in the mountains.
Let's go.
Bye!
-How much further?
-We're almost there.
This is a deer trail.
Let's go.
We're here.
See?
It's a Christmas tree.
You stupid?
It's February.
I'm glad I came.
Hinazuki. You look pretty today.
-What?!
-Do you like her?!
Oh, I said it aloud.
What? No way!
-Good morning, everyone.
-Good morning!
All right, take your seats.
I'm taking attendance.
-Tokiko Asano.
-Here.
-Yuji Arakawa.
-Yukari Ishizaki.
-Here.
Yuuki Ueda.
Idioms are a group of words
that have a different meaning
from their respective definitions
when used together.
It often uses a body part.
FEBRUARY 29TH (MONDAY)
Like your nose, ear, face, and head.
For example, "face the music"
means confronting...
March 1st is the day Hinazuki
is supposed to be killed.
If I can get through that day, then I
can stop the negative chain of events.
My mother... won't have to be killed.
But that's not all.
I'll be able to save
a man awaiting execution
in the world 18 years from now.
I know Jun Shiratori as Yuuki.
In September 1989,
he was arrested on suspicion
of serial kidnapping and murder.
He's always proclaimed his innocence.
All right, done.
Here.
Thank you.
Now you have to remember
to adjust the curve when you fly it.
Satoru.
Seems like you've made a lot of friends.
It's because I did what you said.
No, it's because you got up the courage,
Satoru.
March 1st.
In my first life...
it's the day Kayo was killed.
Hey, let's go
to the science center after this.
-I kind of want to get home early today.
-Come on, keep me company.
Okay.
TOMAKOMAI CITY SCIENCE CENTER
I've always loved this place
since I was little.
Hinazuki was targeted
because she was always alone.
But not this time.
She has me by her side.
So, I guess aspiring manga writers...
like places like this?
Yeah.
-Bye, then.
-Yeah.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I'll come pick you up.
Bye, then! See you tomorrow!
Bye.
The first time I lived this day,
I saw Hinazuki at the park.
But... I didn't call out to her.
That's why... I did today.
I talked to Hinazuki. And her mother.
And...
whoever might be listening nearby.
Yes!
I've changed history!
MARCH 2ND, 1988
Ready?
Happy Birthday, Satoru, Hinazuki!
HAPPY BIRTHDAY SATORU, KAYO
AND MARRIAGE?
-Thank you.
Here come the cakes!
They look delicious!
So, I guess you had the same birthday!
HAPPY BIRTHDAY KAYO
Congratulations!
Here's your presents.
We're giving presents already?
Here, here's mine. Here you go.
-Thanks!
-Here you go.
-Here, Satoru, happy birthday.
-Thanks!
-Here, happy birthday.
-Happy birthday.
-Thanks!
Thank you.
Here, this is from me.
Happy birthday.
Open it.
Sorry, Fujinuma... I...
I couldn't make your present in time.
Don't worry about it.
Give it to me later.
Well, who's ready for some cake?
-Make mine a big piece please.
-You want a big one? All right!
It was my first birthday party, too.
Having friends...
is fun.
We all hung out until it got late.
And I walked Hinazuki home.
I'm really happy...
that I was able...
to become friends with...
you and everyone.
Thank you for today.
I'll give you your present tomorrow.
Okay.
I promise.
See you!
Yes!
I felt all the tension
built up inside me suddenly relax,
and I fell right to sleep.
-Naoki Watanabe.
-Here.
-Good morning!
-Just in the nick of time.
I guess that leaves Kayo
as the only one still late.
What is it, Satoru? Take your seat.
Okay.
Today's March 3rd. Oh, the Hina Festival.
Are some of you girls
having a party tonight?
I guess the boys, too.
Some boys might be excited
about a party if you have a sister.
But let's stay focused today.
Yes.
Hinazuki...
never showed up to school that day.
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto